Sai Koti Reddy Danda

Website: saikotireddy.github.io Email: d.saikotireddy@gmail.com

LinkedIn: saikotireddy

GitHub: github.com/saikotireddy

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My primary research interests lie in Reinforcement Learning and Stochastic Optimal Control. Recently, I started exploring the role of Game Theory in making Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning algorithms more practical to real world applications.

Amongst the application domains, I am interested in Supply chains, Smart grids and robotics. On the software engineering side, I built several Blockchain based solutions for Supply chain Finance and Auto manufacturing sectors. I am currently building AI based solutions for various use-cases in supply chains. More broadly, I am excited by research at the intersection of computer science, mathematics and software engineering.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Science

Bangalore, Karnataka

M.Sc(Engg). in Computer Science, Advisor: Prof. Shalabh Bhatnagar

2014 - 2017

- Thesis: Stochastic Newton methods with enhanced Hessian estimation

NRI Institute of Technology

Guntur, A.P

B.Tech. in Information Technology, GPA: 3.50/4.00

2008 - 2012

- Thesis: An Improvement to k-Nearest Neighbor Classifier

EXPERIENCE

IBM Research India

Bangalore, Karnataka Jul 2017 - Current

Research Engineer position at AI for Supply-chains Group **Projects:** AI for MEBNs, Blockchain Solutions

- AI based analytics for Sterling Commerce Multi Enterprise Business Networks

- Led the development of IPDC Supply Chain and Dealer Finance Blockchain Platform
- Invoice Reconciliation Using Blockchain for Bajaj Auto Limited first of a kind project

Robert Bosch Center for Cyber Physical Systems

Bangalore, Karnataka

Project Assistant position at Stochastic System Lab under Prof. Shalabh Bhatnagar

Dec 2016 - Jun 2017

Project Title: Distributed Multi-Agent Algorithms for Dynamic Control of Microgrids

- Explored the role of reinforcement learning for the distributed control of microgrids
- I also co-written research proposal along with my project mentor, which is accepted and funded by Department of Science Technology - India
- My research work during this period resulted in two top tier publications.

IBM Research India

Bangalore, Karnataka

Summer Intern position at Mathematical Modeling and Industrial Solutions Group

May - Nov 2016

Project Title: Use-cases on Blockchain

- Built initial version of invoice discounting (supply chain finance) project for Mahindra & Mahindra on hypeledger fabric 0.6.

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] S. Nayak, C. A. Ekbote, A. P. S. Chauhan, R. B. Diddigi, P. Ray, A. Sikdar, S. K. R. Danda, and S. Bhatnagar, "A stochastic game framework for efficient energy management in microgrid networks", in *Proceedings of the IEEE PES Innovative Smart Grid Technologies Conference*, 2020.
- [2] K. Sampath, S. K. R. Danda, P. Dayama, and V. D. Pandit, "Collaborative shipping sans orchestrator using blockchain", in *Proceedings of INFORMS Annual Meeting*, 2020.
- [3] K. Sampath, P. Dayama, S. K. R. Danda, and V. D. Pandit, "Invoice reconciliation using blockchain", in *Proceedings of INFORMS Annual Meeting*, 2020.
- [4] S. K. R. Danda, A. Saha, S. G. Tamilselvam, P. Agrawal, and P. Dayama, "Risk averse reinforcement learning for mixed multi-agent environments", in *Proceedings of the AAMAS*, 2019, pp. 2171–2173.
- [5] R. B. Diddigi, S. K. R. Danda, P. KJ, and S. Bhatnagar, "Actor-critic algorithms for constrained multi-agent reinforcement learning", in *Proceedings of the AAMAS*, 2019, pp. 1931–1933.
- [6] D. R. Bharadwaj, S. K. R. Danda, and S. Bhatnagar, "A unified decision making framework for supply and demand management in microgrid networks", in 2018 IEEE International Conference on Communications, Control, and Computing Technologies for Smart Grids (SmartGridComm), IEEE, 2018, pp. 1–7.
- [7] K. Chandramouli, K. Prabuchandran, S. K. R. Reddy Danda, and S. Bhatnagar, "Generalized deterministic perturbations for stochastic gradient search", in 2018 IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC), IEEE, 2018, pp. 5734–5739.
- [8] S. K. R. Danda, L. Prashanth, and S. Bhatnagar, "Improved hessian estimation for adaptive random directions stochastic approximation", in 2016 IEEE 55th Conference on Decision and Control (CDC), IEEE, 2016, pp. 3682–3687.
- [9] S. K. R. Danda, T. H. Sarma, P. Viswanath, and S. Raghava, "An improvement to k-nearest neighbor classifier", 3rd International Conference on Data Management, pp. 314–324, 2013.

PATENTS

- Decentralized Online Multi Agent Visual Question Answering
- System and Method for Factchecking AI models using Blockchain
- Option-based Distributed Reservation System
- Date Quality Control

See full list of defensive publications on saikotireddy.github.io/patents.html

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

•	IBM Research Spotlight Award	2020
•	IBM Client Value Outstanding Technical Achievement Award	2019
•	IBM Research Accomplishment Award	2018
•	MHRD Scholarship for securing rank among the top 1% in Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering	2014 – 2017
•	Secured 2^{nd} rank during my undergraduate studies in Information Technology Department.	2008-2012

SKILLS

• Programming Stack: Python, Golang, Matlab, C

• Frameworks: AngularJS, NodeJS, Dash

• Databases: MongoDB, Neo4j

• Tools: Git, Bash, LATEX

TEACHING

• Teaching Assistant at Neuromatch Academy, July 2020

Computational Neuroscience

 Teaching Assistant at Indian Institute of Science, Fall 2016

Algorithms and Programming

Courses

- Artificial Intelligence: Reinforcement Learning, Machine Learning, Deep Learning
- Computational Methods in Optimization, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Introduction to Big Data, Game Theory
- Mathematics: Stochastic Models and Applications, Linear Algebra and Applications, Real Analysis

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Conference Reviewer:

- IEEE International Conference on Data Mining 2020
- American Control Conference 2020
- IEEE International Conference on Data Mining 2019
- ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management 2019
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control 2017

REFERENCES

• Prof. Shalabh Bhatnagar,

Department of Computer Science and Automation, Indian Institute of Science Bangalore, India.

E-mail: shalabh@csa.iisc.ernet.in

• Dr. Viswanath Pulabaigari,

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Indian Institute of Information Technology, Chittoor, India.

E-mail: viswanth.p@iiits.in viswanth.pulabaigari@gmail.com